Guide to the Malcolm Goldstein Papers MSS.350
Fales Library and Special Collections
- OVERSIZE Series I, 267755
  - Subseries A: Projects A-Z, 267756
    - "Krosnick", [undated]; 267764 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - "The Lamentations of Jeremiah", 1962; 267765 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - "The Life Cycle of Stones" [images for installation], 1987; 267824 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - "The Life Cycle of Stones" [photo-collage], 1987; 267864 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - "Ludlow Blues", July 30, 1963; 267766 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - "Ludlow Blues", July 30, 1963; 267767 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - "Ludlow Blues", July 30, 1963; 267768 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - "Ludlow Blues" Alternative Notations, August 10, 1963; 267769 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - "Majority", 1964; 267770 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - "Music for Four Recorder Players", May 13, 1963; 267771 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - "Paradoxes" [score], February, 1962; 267825 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - "Paradoxes" [score], February 9, 1962; 267826 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - "Paradoxes", [undated]; 267772 (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - "Paradoxes" [transparencies], February 9, 1962; 267773 (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - "Paradoxes", [undated]; 267774 (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - "Passages" [score], July, 1965; 267827 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - "Passages" [score], July, 1965; 267828 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - "Perchance" (for James Waring), [undated]; 267775 (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - "Rokudan", Spring, 1958; 267776 (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - "Rokudan", Spring, 1958; 267777 (Box 44, Folder 21)
    - "Shaking the Dreaming Line" [score; instructions], 1985; 267830 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - "Stillpoint for Brass Quintet" [score], 1962; 267831 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - "Stillpoint for Brass Quintet" [score transparencies], 1962; 267832 (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - "Stillpoint for Brass Quintet" [score transparencies], 1962; 267833 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - "String Quartet", 1958; 267778 (Box 44, Folder 22)
    - "Taut Labyrinth" [1 of 3], 1960; 267779 (Box 44, Folder 23)
    - "Taut Labyrinth" [2 of 3], 1960; 267780 (Box 44, Folder 24)
    - "Taut Labyrinth" [3 of 3], 1960; 267781 (Box 44, Folder 25)
    - "...That Hung Like Fire on Heaven" dedicated to the spirit of Martin Luther King [score], November 28, 1985; 267835 (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - "Trio" Violin, Clarinet (Bb), Cello, March, 1957; 267782 (Box 44, Folder 26)
    - "Two Part Invention" Four Episodes for Piano, December 30, 1957; 267783 (Box 44, Folder 27)
    - "Uber Land Unter" (over land under) with Dorethea Rust, April, 2000; 267784 (Box 44, Folder 28)
    - "Violin and Piano Piece", 1966; 267785 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - "Violin Solos", April 1, 1992; 267786 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - "Yosha's Morning Song, Extended" [Veloxes for CMS Lecture], [undated]; 267787 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - "Z+X Tschaikowsky" [timeline and collage], March 12-14, 1996; 267836 (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - Subseries B: Other Musicians, 267788
    - Cage, John - "Chorals for Violin Solo", [1978]; 267789 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Cage, John - "Music For", 1984; 267790 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Cage, John - "Six Melodies for Violin and Keyboard", 1950; 267791 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Coleman, Ornette - "Trinity", 1986; 267792 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Corner, Philip - "Piece for String Instruments" No. 3, No. 5, No.6, 1958-1959; 267837 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - De Alvear, Maria - "Fuertas" (fountains), August 6, 1994; 267838 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Feldman, Morton - "Extensions I", [undated]; 267793 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Feldman, Morton - "Projection 4", 1959; 267794 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Feldman, Morton - "Verticle Thoughts 2", 1963; 267795 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Flynn, George - "Four Pieces for Violin and Piano", 1965; 267839 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Fox, Jim - "Fire Mountain Burning"; "Below Agua Tibia", 1982; 267840 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Ives, Charles - "First Movement", [undated]; 267796 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Ives, Charles - "Second Movement", [undated]; 267797 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Ives, Charles - "Third Movement", [undated]; 267798 (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Ives, Charles - "Fourth Movement", [undated]; 267841 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Ives, Charles - "Fifth Movement", [undated]; 267842 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Schoenberg, Arnold - "Sechs Kleine Klauenstucke", December, 1957; 267799 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Stravinsky, Igor - "Double Canon" In memoriam Raoul Dufy, October, 1970; 267800 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Vlerk, Lois - "Crane with 1000 Wings", [undated]; 267843 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Wolff, Christian - "Duo for Violinist and Piano", August, 1961; 267884 (Folder 9)
    - Wolpe, Stefan - "Second Piece for Violin Alone", 1966; 267844 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Subseries C: Notebooks and Sketches, 267801
    - Notebook 2: "For Once", [undated]; 267802 (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Notebook 2: Soundings for Solo Violin [mock-up], [undated]; 267845 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Notebook 3: From Wheelock Mountain, [undated]; 267804 (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Notebook 3: Judson Church Performance, [undated]; 267803 (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - Notebook 3: "Piano Studies", [undated]; 267805 (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - Notebook 4: "An old fiddler stomping"; "Book of the Dead"; "Blueberry Picking"; "Upon the seashore of endless worlds", 1967-1974; 267846 (Box 47, Folder 10)
- OVERSIZE Series II, 267806
  - Subseries A: Unpublished Drafts and Interviews, 267849
    - Interview: OP Magazine Walker Arts Center conducted by Steve Peters, Winter, 1980; 267850 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Subseries B: Published, 267807
    - "Arts and Architecture" - "Proof of the Nation" parts I and II by Peter Yates, November, 1965; January, 1966; 267847 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - "EAR New Music News" vol. 13 no.5 - "Soundings for Radio" with Interview, July-August, 1988; 267848 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - "International Festival Musique Actuelle" Victoriaville, May 14-18, 1998; 267808 (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Subseries C: Correspondence, 267809
    - Corner, Philip, February 12, 2000; 267810 (Box 45, Folder 21)
- OVERSIZE Series III, 267811
  - Subseries C: Ephemera, 267812
    - 1962-1968: Columbia Composers, 267813 (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - 1962-1968: [Freda Miller Memorial Concert; Festival of the Avant Garde], 267865 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - 1964: Fluxus, March, 1964; 267883 (Folder 8)
    - 1968: ["Sheep Meadow"], November 6-8, 1968; 267851 (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - 1972-1974: [Experimental Intermedia Foundation; Charles Ives], 267814 (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - 1977: [Experimental Intermedia Foundation: Astrological Bureau of Ideas], April 17, 1977; 267815 (Box 45, Folder 24)
    - 1979: [A Concert of Fluxus Music at Dartmouth; Real Art Ways], 267816 (Box 45, Folder 25)
    - 1979: [New Music America; Walker Arts Center], 267866 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - 1979: [Sound at P.S.1; Avant Garde Festival of New York], 267880 (Folder 4)
    - 1981: [WLRN-FM; New Music Performance Series], 267867 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - 1981: Tour of California, February, 1981; 267868 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - 1982: [Progressions; Austria Tour], 267881 (Folder 7)
    - 1982-1983: [Jackson Mac Low retrospective; D.C. Space; Ear Magazine benefit concert], 267869 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - 1983: UIT Krant [Dutch], November, 1983; 267853 (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - 1983-1984: [Festival D'Automne], Summer 1983- Summer 1984; 267854 (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - 1983: [Andere Avant Garde], Fall, 1983; 267852 (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - 1983-1984: [Holland Tour], Summer 1983- Summer 1984; 267870 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - 1983-1985: [Ornette Coleman Festival; P.S.1], 267882 (Folder 2)
    - 1984-1985: [Holland Tour], Fall 1984- Summer 1985; 267871 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - 1985: [Mobius 'Five Concerts of Improvised Music'], 267855 (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - 1985: ["...that hung like fire on heaven"; "On New Music"], 267872 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - 1986: [Strange Mutations at the Kitchen], January, 1986; 267856 (Box 47, Folder 19)
    - 1986: ["Breath River Route"; NuArts], 267873 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - 1987: [Visual Scores], September 8-October 18, 1987; 267857 (Box 47, Folder 20)
    - 1987-1988: [Absolute Cow; New Music America], 267874 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - 1988: ["Cycladic Imprints" with Carolee Schneeman], 267875 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - 1990: [Europe Tour], Summer, 1990; 267858 (Box 47, Folder 21)
    - 2001: [Festival International de Nouvelle Danse], June 10, 2001; 267859 (Box 47, Folder 22)
    - 2004: [Subtropics], March-April, 2004; 267876 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - 2006: [Barre Phillips; "Hello Goodbye Mr. Bailey"], 267860 (Box 47, Folder 23)
    - 2009: ["Topography of a Sound Mind"], 267877 (Box 48, Folder 16)